The Fireflies’ Promise
The rain and wind won’t bother me in my warm apartment.
And they gave me such a soft futon.
There’s confetti in the bottle.
I feel so content!
Don’t feel so content with just one or two of them.
At this rate, it’ll take you a hundred years to fill the bottle.
That’s okay, Ioryogi-san.
Even if it takes a hundred years, I’ll still try my best.
Do you think I want to be around you for a hundred years?!
Do you understand what you’re supposed to do?
Yes! Heal people’s broken hearts so I can get more confetti.
The birds are singing.
The flowers are sparkling from the morning dew.
They smell nice.
Waking up earlier than normal really lets you experience all sorts of new things.
Can’t you be a little less peppy when just walking?
It’s not like that.
Ah!
This is such a wonderful little lane!
What a beautiful person.
E-Excuse me…
You saw that, huh?
Why were you crying?
I wonder why.
Because the green leaves are pretty… maybe?
The green leaves are so pretty that you cried?
I don’t quite understand it myself.
I’m sorry.
By the way, may I ask your name?
I’m Hanato Kobato.
I’m Kohaku!
Kohaku?
Ioryogi-san, stuffed animals shouldn’t talk.
Kohaku, as in, Kohaku from the heavens?
Heavens?
Yes.
No wonder you smelled different than normal humans.
And who is this, then?
Ioryogi-san.
It’s okay in front of her.
Really?
Ioryogi-san… I’ve heard that name somewhere.
I’ve forgotten.
Listen, it’s not Ioryogi! It just sounds like it!
A name that sounds like it?
Could you be Iorogi-san?
Yes, that’s right.
You two know each other?
Just by name.
To think that Iorogi-san looked so cute…
Well, this form is just temporary while I’m Ioryogi.
Got it. Ioryogi-san it is.
And you’re Kobato-san?
Yes!
I need to water the trees in the
garden before it gets too sunny.
Excuse me.
Yes.
What are you doing?
Ah! You scared me.
I was looking at the leaves.
But no matter how long I look at them, I don’t start crying.
I wonder why.
Who knows. When I look at them, I do cry.
Eh, really? Please tell me why!
Because the person helping me is lazy!
Just thinking about how cleaning up these leaves will eat up the whole day makes me weep.
I’ll do it! I’ll show you how quickly I can finish!
What a birdbrain. I’ll help you out.
Kobato-chan.
Let me help too.
Thank you so much.
What are you doing?
I want to know why Kohaku-san was crying.
If it’s because she’s been hurt, I want to heal her.
I don’t think you’ll get it just from reading that.
But it might give me some kind of hint.
I don’t get it.
You don’t say…
Tomorrow, I will wake up early and try asking Kohaku-san one more time!
I overslept!
I knew this would happen.
She’s not here.
Welcome back.
Thank you for your hard work.
It’s Kohaku-san!
Wait!
Why?
Don’t be rude.
Rude?
If you go over there, you’ll be in the way.
You didn’t have to come all the way here.
You could’ve waited at home.
It’s just that… walking home with you makes me happy.
Also, I wanted to be with you a little bit longer.
They’re flirting like crazy!
What a wonderful mansion.
Something you’ll never have.
You weren’t even invited.
I know, but even if you’re rich, you can still have problems.
Where did you learn something like that?
In the magazine I was reading at that convenience store.
Kudo
Ioryogi-san?
Yeah?
When will it be okay for me to call out to them?
No, that’s not the problem.
I’m sorry, I couldn’t keep my promise today.
You are open the entire night, Shuichiro-san.
And the patients are very important.
You are both important.
You really weren’t invited. Let’s go home.
H-Hey!
Spirit of the water.
Please, answer my call.
Lend your powers to water the trees.
Gather yourself to save these lives.
Fill the sky, oh blessed rain!
So pretty.
Kobato-san?
Ioryogi-san?
Watch what you’re watering!
I’m sorry. I’m so sorry!
I’m really sorry.
No, I’m sorry too. I apologize for coming here uninvited.
Why are you here?
Actually…
Yesterday, I happened to see you with a man.
Eh?
I’m sorry, but I followed you.
But… I still don’t understand why you cried.
It’s been bothering me.
I don’t understand it well myself.
But when I see something pretty, I want to show it to Shuichiro-san as well.
It reminds me of him.
Okay.
When I think about Shuichiro-san…
Think about him?
I feel a sudden ache in my chest.
An ache?
You could say it feels fuzzy.
When I’m with Shuichiro-san, I always feel so content.
And when he sometimes shows me his bashful smile…
…the memories just overflow me with emotions.
Like this.
Like this?
And the tears just start flowing.
Ah… I still don’t understand.
I’m sorry, I just can’t explain it very well.
For crying out loud, you shed tears because you’re so in love that it hurts!
Love?
I see, love.
I get it. It’s love.
You look like you don’t.
In love, troubles are an unavoidable aspect. I read it in a magazine.
Kohaku-san, is anything troubling you?
Let’s see…
Yes?
You could say the way Shuichiro-san is always busy troubles me.
We haven’t even done one of those “dates.”
Date?
Going with the person you love to someplace like an amusement park.
It’s something like that.
An amusement park… date.
Leave it up to me, Kohaku-san!
I’ll do my best!
If she can go on an amusement park date with Shuichiro-san, Kohaku-san’s heart will heal.
First, I have to learn about amusement parks.
This is an amusement park?
It looks like fun.
Eh?
Tickets are 3000 yen?!
I guess you need money for amusement parks.
But I don’t have any money. What should I do?
Don’t ask me.
Anyway, trying to heal Kohaku is…
Ah! Ioryogi-san!
Eh?
First place, a trip to Hawaii!
Second place, a trip to the hot springs!
Third place, tickets to the amusement park!
Spin it around and get a ball with the right color to win.
We’re inviting pairs to try.
Now, use your fortune tickets please! Your fortune tickets.
Amazing! We can win amusement park tickets over there!
Here you go.
Miss, where’s your fortune ticket?
Huh?
If you don’t have a ticket, you can’t participate.
Before I can get the amusement park ticket, I have to have a fortune ticket?
Fortune ticket…
It’s also natural to feel dejected no matter what you do.
And anyway, Kohaku…
A fortune ticket…
Nobody’s dropped one?
What?! You mean you haven’t given up yet?!
Geez, you look pretty chipper for someone who’s dejected…
It’s a fortune ticket!
It’s a fortune ticket. Let me spin it please!
Here!
G-Go ahead.
I’m going to try my best.
Amusement park tickets.
Congratulations! You won!
Eh! I did?
You’ve got to be kidding me!
Fifth place!
A stuffed alligator animal. Give it lots of love!
Winning something like this is just a bother.
Why didn’t you refuse it?
He was so kind when he gave it to me. Refusing it would have been rude.
But…
If it’s not the amusement park tickets, then it’s no good.
I-I’m sorry.
Fujimoto-san!
You! Stop daydreaming!
Are you delivering these newspapers?
Yeah.
But I heard from Sayaka-sensei that your part-time job is delivering pizzas.
I do that as well.
You’re that busy?
What’s that?
An alligator I won in a lottery.
But the alligator is no good.
Amusement park tickets.
Yeah. I got them from my part-time job.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Can you please give these tickets to me?
Excuse me? Don’t be ridiculous.
Ah! What if I trade the alligator for the tickets?
No good. I don’t need it.
Please!
It’s so Kohaku-san can have a date at the amusement park!
Here!
With these, you can have a date with Shuichiro-san!
Just do what you want, why don’t you.
Those newspapers…
To get these, I have to help deliver them.
To get these tickets, you have to deliver newspapers?
Yes! Please, take them.
Thank you very much.
But I can’t accept them.
Why is that?
Shuichiro-san is busy, so those tickets are useless.
But on the other hand, those tickets shouldn’t go to waste…
That’s it! Kobato-san, you should go!
M-Me?
Yes, with Ioryogi-san.
What?
Ah, with Ioryogi-san…
Stop imagining that!
I can’t do that! If you can’t go with Shuichiro-san, then there’s no point.
But I really think it’s impossible.
And…
I really can’t be self-centered.
That’s…
…selfish, isn’t it?
To me, it looked like Shuichiro-san really enjoys the time he spends with you.
I saw how happy you looked when you were with him.
Shuichiro-san must think the world of you, just like you think the world of him.
I’m sure he wants to have a date as well.
Kobato-san…
Shuichiro-san?
Can we really have those tickets?
Of course!
Here, please!
Shuichiro-san, can we really go together?
I don’t hate the ferris wheel.
I can’t see them.
Of course not! Let’s go home.
Okay…
I’m sure they’re having a lot of fun.
Who knows.
Ushagi-san?
A messenger from the heavens.
The heavens? Another acquaintance?
A time limit?
Until when?
The bottle has to be full when the four seasons have passed?
Huh?
You heard, right?
Yes. There’s a time limit now.
When the four seasons have passed, right?
In other words, you have one year to fill the bottle.
If you can’t do it…
…I cannot go to the place I want to.
Look, nothing’s been added.
They’re not shaking.
Do you know why?
No, I don’t.
I wonder if it’s because I haven’t healed Kohaku-san’s heart.
It’s because those who are already happy don’t need healing.
So she wasn’t hurt!
And you’re happy about this?!
A hundred points!
Eh?! A hundred points?
Minus!
Minus… hundred points?
You picked the wrong person. Not realizing that fact costs you points.
But the fact that she’s happy makes me happy anyway!
Don’t be so carefree! You have just one year and you have to work relentlessly!
Yes! I’ll do my best!
Again with such a frivolous face.
It is not!
Didn’t I say you have to work relentlessly?
What does a relentless face look like?
Like this! Can you do it?